<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xml:id="ivy.addons.libraries">
	<title>Libraries</title>
	<para> The IvyAddOns project contains (executable) libraries that can be used outside of
		Xpert.ivy (e.g. on the client or from within other applications) to communicate or otherwise
		interact with Xpert.ivy. The purpose and usage of those libraries is explained in this
		chapter. </para>
	<sect1 xml:id="ivy.addons.libraries.processstarter">
		<title>IvyProcessStarter.jar</title>
		<sect2>
			<title>Purpose</title>
			<para> Normally Xpert.ivy Applications are started by clicking on a Link in a Web
				browser. However, often afterwards the browser is not needed anymore and, in fact,
				wouldn't really have been required in the first place, were it not for the reason
				that there is no other way to start an Xpert.ivy application. </para>
			<para> With the <filename>IvyProcessStarter.jar</filename>, which is located in the
				IvyAddOns <filename>lib/</filename> folder (switch to the Java or Resource
				perspective to see it), one can start Xpert.ivy applications with a single click
				from the desktop, without having to use a browser. The following image shows three
				common ways to do so on a windows desktop: either from the start menu (1), from the
				quick start tool bar (2) or with a short cut icon on the desktop. </para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Libraries/processShortcuts.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<para> Once such a Shortcut is installed, the user simply clicks on it and the linked
				Xpert.ivy application starts directly (via Java) without the need of having to open
				a browser beforehand. </para>
			<note>
				<para>Although the screenshots in this section show Windows desktops only, similar
					usage is possible on other operating systems by using the similar mechanisms and
					the same <filename>IvyProcessStarter.jar</filename>. Usage within shellscripts
					is also possible (see section Command line arguments below).</para>
			</note>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>Usage and Installation</title>
			<para> Copy the <filename>IvyProcessStarter.jar</filename> from the <emphasis
					role="italic">IvyAddOns</emphasis> project to the client machine (e.g. to
					<filename>C:/Programme/ProcessStarter</filename>). </para>
			<para> Right-click on the JAR and select <emphasis role="italic">Send to... > Desktop
					(create shortcut)</emphasis>. As a result of this, a shortcut icon will be
				created on the Desktop. </para>
			<para> Right-click on the shortcut icon and select <emphasis role="italic"
				>Properties</emphasis>. Configure the shortcut as depticted on the following image: <mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/Libraries/processShortcutConfiguration.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject> Once you've clicked on <emphasis role="italic">Ok</emphasis> you can
				double click the created shortcut to start the application referred by the
					<filename>*.ivp</filename> link. The created shortcut can be duplicated and
				copied to the start menu or the quick start toolbar. You may also select another
				symbol for the shortcut (check your OS documentation about how to do this). </para>
			<tip>
				<para>Use double quotes around your (windows) path names that you use to execute the
					shortcut (e.g. for the location of <filename>java.exe</filename> or the location
					of the <filename>IvyProcessStarter.jar</filename>) to prevent problems with
					special characters or spaces inside the file path.</para>
				<para>Use <filename>javaw.exe</filename> instead of <filename>java.exe</filename> to
					prevent the (temporary) opening of a command window during the startup
				process.</para>
			</tip>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>Command line arguments</title>
			<para>Here's the help that is output when <command>java -jar
				IvyProcessStarter.jar</command> is invoked from the command line. You should not use
				any of the possible switches for a shortcut as described above.
				<screen>
Usage:
    	<command>StartJnlpLink [-help] [-debug] &lt;link></command>
Purpose:
    Retrieves the JNLP file at the given link location and starts it with the system's default application for '.jnlp' files.
Arguments:
    	<command>&lt;link></command> must be a HTTP-URL that points to the contents of a valid JNLP file (e.g. an URL to a ../ivy/pro/../myProcessStart.ivp)
Switches:
    	<command>-debug</command> prints some verbose debug output
    	<command>-help</command> prints this text
				</screen></para>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
